Finding Aid for Robert Crouse papers, 1846 and 1856-1866
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert Crouse papers 1846 and 1856-1866
Crouse, Robert, 1813-1869.
1.5 linear feet (in 3 boxes) and 1 roll microfilm
851009 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of members of the Crouse family (donor nos. 5435 and 9730 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research. Researchers must use microfilm of the Correspndence series.
The correspondence series, which includes Civil War era letters, has been microfilmed.
Robert Crouse was born in Avon, New York on October 2, 1813. He came to Michigan in 1832 and from 1834 to 1841, he was merchant at Kensington. He subsequently became a mill owner and farmer in Hartland, Michigan. In 1860, he became interested in real estate and the manufacture of salt at East Saginaw, and in 1862, he built the Crouse block and the Everett House in Hartland. He died in February 1869.
The Robert Crouse papers consist of Civil War Era correspondence, including letters from soldiers describing camp life and other war-time activities. There is also letters received from businessmen in Michigan and New York state relating to business transactions. These letters date from the 1850s and 1860. Finally, the papers include business invoices and express and railroad receipts.
Subjects:
Hartland (Mich.)--Economic conditions.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
- Correspondence
  - 1856 and 1862 (Reel 1)
    (access to originals is restricted)
  - 1863 (Reel 1)
  - 1864 (Reel 1)
  - 1858-1865 (Civil War and personal) (Box 2)
- Business correspondence
  (letters received; arranged by location)
  - Oakland County merchants (Box 2)
  - Detroit merchants (Box 2)
  - Bay City, Frankenmuth, and Saginaw merchants (Box 2)
  - Ingham and Washtenaw county merchants (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Michigan merchants (Box 2)
  - New York State merchants, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Out-of-state merchants (non-New York) (Box 2)
  - Washington D.C. officials (Box 2)
- Other business papers
  - Invoices, 1854-1865, 34 folders (Box 3)
  - Express and railroad receipts, 1856-1866, 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1846 and 1857-1858 (Box 3)